export default Dpe7 = [
    {
        question: "1. Which of the following elements family belongs to 16(VI A) group ?",
        options: ["Carbon family",
            "Oxygen family",
            "Boron family",
            "Nitrogen family"],
        correct_option: "Oxygen family"
    },
    {
        question: "2. Which of the following is d-block element ?",
        options: ["Scandium",
            "Sodium",
            "Aluminium",
            "Carbon"],
        correct_option: "Scandium"
    },
    {
        question: "3. Which of the following elements are generally semi-conductors ?",
        options: ["B",
            "Ge",
            "All",
            "Si"],
        correct_option: "All"
    },
    {
        question: "4. Number of vertical columns in the modern periodic table are",
        options: ["7",
            "8",
            "18",
            "10"],
        correct_option: "18"
    },
    {
        question: "5. Which of the following species does have electrons equal to 18 ?",
        options: ["Cl-",
            "All",
            "Ca+2",
            "K+"],
        correct_option: "All"
    },
    {
        question: "6. The following is not a Dobereiner Triad",
        options: ["Cl , Br , l",
            "B , Be , C",
            "Li , Na , K",
            "Ca , Sr , Ba"],
        correct_option: "Cl , Br , l"
    },
    {
        question: "7. M+ + IE2 \longrightarrow M+2(g) + e- . This represents",
        options: ["Ionization energy",
            "Second ionization energy",
            "Electron affinity",
            "Electro negativity"],
        correct_option: "Second ionization energy"
    },
    {
        question: "8. Example of a molecule having pyramidal shape is....",
        options: ["H2O",
            "CO2",
            "NH3",
            "BeCl2"],
        correct_option: "NH3"
    },
    {
        question: "9. Which is the wrong sequence of the elements belongs to alkali metals ?",
        options: ["9 , 17 , 35 , 53",
            "37 , 19 , 3 , 55",
            "12 , 20 , 56 , 88",
            "1 , 12 , 30 , 4 , 62"],
        correct_option: "37 , 19 , 3 , 55"
    },
    {
        question: "10. Elements from 58Ce to 71Lu are called .",
        options: ["Inert gases",
            "Transition elements",
            "Actinoides",
            "Lanthanoids"],
        correct_option: "Lanthanoids"
    },
    {
        question: "11. Electronic configuration from ns1 to ns2 are called",
        options: ["f - block elements",
            "p - block elements",
            "d - block elements",
            "s - block elements"],
        correct_option: "s - block elements"
    },
    {
        question: "12. Gallium is named by Mendeleeff as",
        options: ["Eka silicon",
            "None",
            "Eka aluminium",
            "Eka boron"],
        correct_option: "Eka aluminium"
    },
    {
        question: "13. Elements belonging to the same period have",
        options: ["Same number of shell",
            "Same valency electrons",
            "Same atomic size",
            "Same electron affinity"],
        correct_option: "Same number of shell"
    },
    {
        question: "14. Electronic configuration of an atom is 2, 8, 7 to which of the following elements would it be chemically similar ?",
        options: ["Phosphorous(Z = 15)",
            "Argon(Z = 18)",
            "Nitrogen(Z = 7)",
            "Fluorine(Z = 9)"],
        correct_option: "Fluorine(Z = 9)"
    },
    {
        question: "15. Which of the following property is measured in 'pm'(pico meter) units ?",
        options: ["Electron affinity",
            "Atomic radius",
            "Electronegativity",
            "Ionization energy"],
        correct_option: "Atomic radius"
    },
    {
        question: "16. A Dobereiner's Traid in the following .....",
        options: ["H , He , Li",
            "Cl , Br , l",
            "C , N , O",
            "H , Na , Cl"],
        correct_option: "Cl , Br , l"
    },
    {
        question: "17. Which of the is defined as the number of positive charges in the atom of element ?",
        options: ["Valency",
            "Atomic weight",
            "Atomic number",
            "Atomic radius"],
        correct_option: "Atomic number"
    },
    {
        question: "18. What is the structure of Water molecule ?",
        options: ["None",
            "Pyramidal shape",
            "V shape",
            "Linear structure"],
        correct_option: "V shape"
    },
    {
        question: "19. In the Dobereiner's Traid , the atomic weight of middle element is equal to",
        options: ["Average of atomic weight of two elements",
            "Sum of atomic weight of two elements",
            "Ratio of atomic weight of two elements",
            "Product of atomic weight of two elements"],
        correct_option: "Product of atomic weight of two elements"
    },
    {
        question: "20. Periodicity is observed in periodic table due to reappearance of similar valency shell configuration after regular interval of",
        options: ["1 , 3 , 5 , 7 , 9",
            "5 , 10 , 15 , 20 , 25",
            "20 , 30 , 40 , 50",
            "2 , 8 , 8 ,18 , 18 , 32"],
        correct_option: "5 , 10 , 15 , 20 , 25"
    },
    {
        question: "21. The element with atomic number 7 is found in",
        options: ["2nd period IVA group",
            "1st period IA group",
            "2nd period VA group",
            "2nd period IIIA group"],
        correct_option: "1st period IA group"
    },
    {
        question: "22. Elements with electronic configuration ns1 and ns2 are called",
        options: ["d - block elements",
            "s - block elements",
            "f - block elements",
            "p - block elements"],
        correct_option: "s - block elements"
    },

    {
        question: "23. Arrange the following elements in the order of their decreasing metallic character Na , Si , Cl , Mg , Al",
        options: ["Al > Na > Si >Cl > Mg",
            "Na > Mg > Al > Si > Cl",
            "Cl > Si > Al > Mg > Na",
            "Na > Al > Mg > Cl > Si"],
        correct_option: "Cl > Si > Al > Mg > Na"
    },
    {
        question: "24. Number of elements present in period-2 of the long form of  periodic table",
        options: ["18",
            "32",
            "2",
            "8"],
        correct_option: "8"
    },

    {
        question: "25. By analyzing which patterns the modern periodic table is proposed ?",
        options: ["X - ray ",
            "gamma - ray ",
            "beta - ray ",
            "alpha - ray"],
        correct_option: "alpha - ray"
    },

]